最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
专注GOT剧集
翻译 埃尔夫歪
翻译  蓝山脚下的林顿
翻译 Reasno
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译 依依Eva
校对 屈畅   赵琳
派
Pyke
克
城
校对 拉拉兄控凯冯  北落师门
后期 SerGawen@huiji.wiki
临冬城
Winterfell
监制 北落师门
监制 临冬城的狮子
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki
技术支持 灰机T.R.A.N.S.
绝境长城 the Wall
策划 衣柜军团
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huiji.wiki          Heichengbao
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
冰火中文维基
ASOIAF.HuiJi.WiKi
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第五集
门
the Door
请进
Yes?
珊莎·史塔克
夫人 这是您的
For you, my lady.
鼹鼠村离这多远？
How far is Mole's Town?
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”
珊莎
Sansa.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
听说您逃出临冬城 我万分惊惧
When I heard you had escaped Winterfell, I feared the worst.
见您毫发无损
You have no idea how happy I am
我欣喜至极
to see you unharmed.
毫发无损？
Unharmed?
你来这做什么？
What are you doing here?
我率谷地的骑士北上 前来救援
I rode north with the Knights of the Vale to come to your aid.
此刻他们正在卡林湾扎营
They're encamped at Moat Cailin as we speak.
前来救援？
To come to my aid?
你了解拉姆斯么？
Did you know about Ramsay?
如果你不了解 你就是个白痴
If you didn't know, you're an idiot.
如果你了解 你就是我的敌人
If you did know, you're my enemy.
想听听我们新婚之夜的故事么？
Would you like to hear about our wedding night?
他没有打我的脸
He never hurt my face.
他需要我这张脸 奈德·史塔克之女的这张脸
He needed my face, the face of Ned Stark's daughter.
但对我身体的其余部分
But the rest of me,
他肆意妄为
he did what he liked with the rest of me
只要我还能为他生出继承人
as long as I could still give him an heir.
你觉得他做了什么？
What do you think he did?
我无法想象……
I can't begin to contemplate...
你觉得他对我做了什么？
What do you think he did to me?
珊莎夫人在问你问题
Lady Sansa asked you a question.
他打了您
He beat you.
是的 他很享受
Yes, he enjoyed that.
你觉得他还做了什么？
What else do you think he did?
－珊莎 我……－还有什么？
- Sansa, I... - What else?
他割伤了您？
Did he cut you?
－看来你的确一直很了解拉姆斯啊－我不了解
- Maybe you did know about Ramsay all along. - I didn't know.
我还以为你知道所有人的秘密呢
I thought you knew everyone's secrets.
我犯了一个错误 可怕的错误
I made a mistake, a horrible mistake.
我低估了一个陌生人
I underestimated a stranger.
他做的其它事
The other things he did,
都是夫人小姐们无法说出口的
ladies aren't supposed to talk about those things,
却会是妓院老板们永远的谈资
but I imagine brothel keepers talk about them all the time.
我依然能感觉到
I can still feel it.
不是说它依然能刺痛我柔软的内心
I don't mean in my tender heart it still pains me so.
而是此刻站在这里我仍能感受到他对我的身体做了什么
I can still feel what he did in my body standing here right now.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你说过会保护我
You said you would protect me.
我会的 你要相信我 我的承诺出自真心
And I will. You must believe me when I tell you that I will.
我不会再相信你了 我也不再需要你了
I don't believe you anymore. I don't need you anymore.
你无法保护我
You can't protect me.
如果我让布蕾妮杀死你
You won't even be able to protect yourself
你甚至无法保护自己
if I tell Brienne to cut you down.
我为什么不这么做呢？
And why shouldn't I?
您要我乞求饶命么？
Do you want me to beg for my life?
如果这是您希望的 那么我会的
If that's what you want, I will.
您要求的任何事 只要我能力所及
Whatever you ask that is in my power,
我都会做的
I will do.
如果我要你现在死在这里呢？
What if I want you to die here and now?
那么我就去死
Then I will die.
你从谋害我家人的恶魔手中救出我
You freed me from the monsters who murdered my family
然后将我拱手送给另一个害我家人的恶魔
and you gave me to other monsters who murdered my family.
滚回你的卡林湾
Go back to Moat Cailin.
我和兄长将靠自己的力量夺回北境
My brother and I will take back the North on our own.
我不想再见到你
I never want to see you again.
若能使过去的一切不发生 我愿做任何事
I would do anything to undo what's been done to you.
但我知道我不能
I know that I can't.
可以允许我离开前再说一句么？
Will you allow me to say one more thing before I go?
您的外叔祖父黑鱼布林登
Your great-uncle Brynden the Blackfish
已集结徒利家族剩余军队 夺回了奔流城
has gathered what remains of the Tully forces and retaken Riverrun.
您也许会考虑联系他
You might consider seeking him out.
将来您也许需要一支忠诚的军队
The time may come when you need an army loyal to you.
军队我已经有了
I have an army.
你哥哥的军队
Your brother's army.
同父异母的哥哥
Half-brother.
你还没有准备好
You're not ready.
趁还来得及 你应该赶紧回家去
You should go home before it's too late.
你永远不会成为我们中的一员 史塔克小姐
You'll never be one of us, Lady Stark.
贾昆·赫加尔
无面者
她讲得有理
She has a point.
最早的无面者没有谁是贵族出身
None of the first Faceless Men were born to lords and ladies.
他们最初都是瓦雷利亚矿井中的奴隶
They began as slaves in the mines of Valyria.
谁是第一个无面者？
Who was the first?
无名之辈
He was no one.
千面之神教会他如何褪去面容
The Many-Faced God taught him how to shed his face
如何送出馈赠
and how to give the gift.
他教会了其他人 以此换来了他们的侍奉
The man taught others in exchange for their service.
更多人侍奉 更多的馈赠被送出
Many served, many more gifts were given.
很快所有的奴隶主和监工都消失了
Soon all the masters and overseers were gone
而无面者随之逃离
and the Faceless Men fled.
去了哪里？
Where did they go?
这里
Here.
他们建立了自由城邦布拉佛斯和这座黑白之院
They founded the Free City of Braavos and built this house.
这些都是不装戴他人面孔之时
These were the faces they wore in life
他们自己的面孔
when they were not wearing others.
无面先人
The first Faceless Men.
而现在 若女孩怀着渴望的话
And now a girl is one of them,
就能成为其中之一
if a girl desires.
女孩没有什么渴望
A girl has no desires.
目标是谁？
Who?
一个女演员 自称克连恩夫人
An actress who calls herself Lady Crane.
她在西尔巴广场的剧院演出
She performs at the theater in Sheelba Square.
这已是女孩的第二次机会
A girl has been given a second chance.
不会再有第三次了
There will not be a third.
无论怎样
One way or another,
圣堂将会新添一张面庞
a face will be added to the hall.
啊 死于野猪的獠牙
Oh, murdered by a boar.
这个巨大的长毛婊子
The great big hairy whore.
獠牙刺进 拖出我的肠子
He dug in his tusks and dug out my guts
我就要不行了
and soon I am no more.
啊 父亲 您须卧床休息
Oh, come, Father, in bed you must lie.
我爱您 父亲 请别离我而去
I love you, Father. Please don't die.
贱人住口！瑟曦 给我倒酒
Shut up, you swine! Cersei, more wine.
我感到的凛冬的寒风吹过大地
I feel the winds of winter as they lick across the land.
吾儿将孤身坐上冰冷的王座
And our son alone on that cold, cold throne
无人扶助
without a guiding hand.
何人教他君临天下？何人教他自信优雅？
Who will teach him strength? Who will teach him grace?
当他需板起面孔 何人可以求助？
To whom will he turn when it's time to learn to look darkness in the face?
奈德·史塔克会教他 现在接着给我倒酒
Ned Stark will do fine. Now bring me more wine.
这里发生了什么？
What's happened here, then?
奈德·史塔克 他找你来
He brought you here, Ned Stark,
因你是最智慧之人
'cause you're the brightest fellow in the land.
汝将为王
You should be king of us all
而吾为汝之首相
and I should be your Hand.
我们北境人都是一把好手
We men of the North are right good hands
让人们把法纪遵守
at keeping people lawful.
我寻求他的准许
I'd ask him for permission,
他却闻起来一股恶臭
but he smells too bloody awful.
吾将死！吾将死！
I die! I die!
如今吾只有卧躺于斯
And here I now must lie.
哦 喔 哦 不
Oh, woe. Oh, no.
哦 吾将死
Oh, I am about to go.
你是否愿继续出任乔佛里的首相
Will you stay on as Joffrey's Hand?
铁王座才是我所求
The Iron Throne's what I demand.
－你不可以－我可以
- You cannot. - I can.
－你不会的－我会
- You will not. - I will.
－你不敢－我敢
- You dare not. - I dare yes.
－继承的顺位 －那有什么意义？
- The line of succession. - What's that mean?
－正当的程序 －那又有什么关系？
- The proper progression. - What's that mean?
－ 合法的登基 － 那算什么玩意？
- The lawful ascension. - What's that mean?
快滚开 还我属于我的王座
So move along, give me my chair
不然我找你麻烦
and there won't be no more trouble.
我们曾有凿凿共识
But we had a deal all done and dusted.
如今我看你不可信任
I'm starting to think you can't be trusted.
救救我父
Save my father.
你不该杀他 处决他对你唯害无他
Truly you should. Killing the man will do you no good.
－ 求你救救他 － 给他慈悲
- Save him, please. - Show him mercy.
让人们知道一个好国王有多悲悯
Show the people what a good king should be.
我的人民 你们可以放心
Good people, you may all relax.
吾父的友人当能幸免……
My father's friend shall be spared the...
父亲！不！
Father! No!
哦 父亲
Oh, Father.
不必担心！
Worry not!
一切皆好
All is well.
我现有一封命令
I have here a decree
来自我父泰温·兰尼斯特
from my father Tywin Lannister,
世上最富有之人
the richest man you'll see.
他任命我为御前首相
He proclaims me Hand of the King.
我将终身任职
The position's mine for life.
且他已许我
And he's given me permission to take
娶珊莎为妻
Sansa as my wife.
你将知 纵我身材缺残
You'll learn that what I lack in height,
我将用欲望来填
I make up for in appetite.
忘掉你的悲惨处境
So let's forget about your plight,
来把我们的新婚之夜排演
and go rehearse our wedding night.
是疣子 两个疣子
It's a wart. Two warts.
我那玩意儿上长了两个疣子
I've got two fucking warts on my cock.
不用担心 亲 过个五六年就消了
Well, don't worry, love. They usually go away in five or six years.
哦 亲爱的 把这件洗了 已经臭了
Oh, wash this, darling. It stinks of me.
亲爱的 你能做的更好 比安卡 你一定会的
You can do better, Bianca, dear. You must do.
我只有两句台词
I had two lines.
两句也很重要 你演得太假了
There are no small parts. You rang very false.
我演得假？
I rang very false?
美人儿 你需要的是 有人来教你怎么演
What you need, love, is for someone to ring you true.
昨晚你可没抱怨我
You weren't complaining about me last night.
来点葡萄酒吗 克连恩夫人？
May I get you some wine, Lady Crane?
我是只喝朗姆酒的 博博诺
I'm a rum girl, Bobono.
如果你还想更亲密 就得知道这些
You need to know that if we're going to be intimate.
我们当然会更亲密
Of course we're going to be intimate.
只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time.
敬我们的孩子
To our children.
愿他们有你的才华
May they have your talent.
和你肮脏的心灵
And your filthy mind.
女孩会在朗姆酒里下毒
A girl will poison the rum.
只有克连恩夫人喝朗姆酒
Lady Crane is the only one who drinks it.
如果女孩能用大厅里的某个面孔……
If a girl could use one of the faces from the hall...
女孩还没准备好
A girl is not ready.
她是个好演员
She's a good actress.
某人也听说了
So a man has heard.
她看上去像个好人
Seems like a decent woman.
难道只有坏人会死吗？
Does death only come for the wicked and leave the decent behind?
不是
No.
是谁要她死？
Who wants her dead?
不重要 代价已付讫
That does not matter. The price was paid.
是那个年轻的女演员
The younger actress.
她因为克连恩夫人比她好而心生嫉妒
She's jealous because Lady Crane is better.
女孩必须决定她是不是要侍奉千面之神
A girl must decide if she wants to serve the Many-Faced God.
女孩已决定好了
A girl has decided.
侍奉之人不问问题
A servant does not ask questions.
布兰·史塔克
三眼乌鸦
先知
森林之子
不！不要！不要！
No! No! No!
是你们
It was you.
你们创造了白鬼
You made the white walkers.
我们当时在打仗
We were at war.
我们遭到屠杀
We were being slaughtered.
圣树被砍伐
Our sacred trees cut down.
我们必须保护自己
We needed to defend ourselves.
敌人是谁？
From whom?
你们
From you.
你们人类
From men.
我们在淹神的注视下起誓
We speak in the presence of the Drowned God.
以淹神的名义在此集合
In his name we gather today
选出一位新国王来领导我们
to choose a new king as our leader.
谁将成为我们的王？
Who makes a claim?
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
我是亚拉·葛雷乔伊
I am Yara Greyjoy,
铁群岛之王巴隆·葛雷乔伊
daughter of Balon Greyjoy,
的女儿
King of the Iron Islands.
我欲登王座
I claim the Salt Throne.
我们从来没有过女王 从来没有
We've never had a queen. Not once.
我们从没做过的事情多了
There are many things we've never done.
我们从未扬名于世
We've never made our mark upon the world.
除了我们的劫掠船队在他们的地盘四处剽掠的时候
The great lords of Westeros pay us no mind
那些维斯特洛的王公贵族们对我们从来嗤之以鼻
until our little raids buzz through their kingdoms
等到他们觉得烦了
long enough to become a nuisance.
就来攻打我们
Then they swat us down.
征服我们 羞辱我们
They conquer us, humiliate us,
随后扬长而去重又对我们视而不见
and go right back to forgetting we exist.
是啊！
Aye!
- 我们是海上民族  - 对！
- We are a sea people. - Aye!
- 海神才是我们的神  - 对！
- Our god is a sea god. - Aye!
我若为女王 将打造一支舰队……
When I am queen, we will build a fleet that...
- 你成不了女王！ - 我还没有说完！
- You shall not be queen! - I am not finished!
不 你已经说完了！女人没法领导我们
Yes, you are! A woman will not lead us.
更何况巴隆的嫡子已经重回铁群岛
Not when Balon's own male heir has returned.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
我是席恩·葛雷乔伊……
I am Theon Greyjoy...
巴隆·葛雷乔伊仅存的儿子
last living son of Balon Greyjoy.
她才该是你们的统治者
And she is your rightful ruler.
没错！
Aye!
在这儿有好些人
Those of you that have sailed under her,
曾在她的指挥下扬帆出海
and there are many of you here,
- 你们知道她是什么样的 - 没错！
- you know what she is. - Aye!
- 她是个掠夺者 - 对！
- She is a reaver. - Aye!
- 她是个战士 - 对！
- She is a warrior. - Aye!
她是个铁种！
She is ironborn!
没错！
Aye!
我们没有更好的人选了
We will find no better leader.
她就是我们的女王
This is our queen.
亚拉！亚拉！亚拉！
Yara! Yara! Yara!
我是攸伦·葛雷乔伊
I'm Euron Greyjoy.
我亦欲登王座
I claim the Salt Throne.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊
巴隆之弟
亚拉侄女
Niece.
席恩侄儿
Nephew.
小席恩
Little Theon.
听说你把一切都搞砸了
Heard you managed to fuck things right into the ground.
拿下了一个根本守不住的城堡
Captured a castle you couldn't keep.
最后自己成了俘虏
Got yourself taken prisoner.
甚至谣传说你下面没了
Even heard you have no cock.
难怪你觉得女人可以当王
Explains why you think a woman can be king.
你什么时候回来的 叔叔
When did you return, Uncle?
几天前吧
A few days ago.
要做一些
I had some things to take care of.
早该做的事儿
Long overdue.
很高兴你能来
I'm glad you're here.
我现在知道登上大位之后当做的第一件事是什么了
Now I know what my first act as queen will be.
将杀父仇人枭首
To execute the man who killed my father.
是我干的
I did.
我杀了他
I killed him.
在索桥上把他扔了下去
Threw him right over a rope bridge
看着他掉下去
and watched him fall.
跟着他没有出路
He was leading us nowhere
如果不是我杀了他 没有出路的日子还将继续
and we would still be heading there if it weren't for me.
没人爱戴他了 没人愿意追随他了
No one loved him. No one wanted to follow him.
他将我们带入了两场毫无胜算的仗
He led us into two wars we couldn't win.
我很抱歉没早点杀了他
I apologize to you all for not killing him years ago.
你想杀也杀不了
That would have been hard to do.
你根本就不在铁群岛
You weren't here.
我最后一次听到你的消息是你在优哉游哉周游世界
Last I heard, you were gallivanting around the world having a grand old time.
优哉游哉？
Gallivanting?
你下面没了就学着这么说话了吗？
That the sort of thing you start to say once your dick gets chopped off?
是不是维斯特洛的老爷们教你这么说话的？
Did the great lords of Westeros teach you words like that?
你不在这儿
You were gone.
亚拉却在
Yara was here.
成长为铁种 领导铁种
Being ironborn. Leading ironborn.
时刻准备着带领我们寻回荣耀
Getting ready to bring us back to glory.
她又要怎么做到呢？
And how will she do that?
我会打造一支有史以来最大的舰队
I will build the largest fleet the world has ever seen.
不错不错 只不过我才是打造铁舰队的那个人
Right idea, except I'm the one who's going to build the Iron Fleet
因为只有我知道该怎样利用这支舰队
because I'm the one who knows how to use it.
我周游过世界
I've been all over the world.
你们的见识加起来也比不上我
I've seen more of it than all of you combined.
这海的对面 有一位人物
And across the sea there is a person
她和我们一样痛恨维斯特洛的贵族老爷
who hates the great lords of Westeros just as much as we do.
她有一支大军
Someone with a large army,
有三条龙 却没有个丈夫
three large dragons, and no husband.
我将会打造这支舰队
I'm going to build that fleet
然后我要优哉游哉地过去
and I'm going to gallivant right over
把这支舰队交到丹妮莉丝·坦格利安手中
and give it to Daenerys Targaryen
外加我的这杆长枪
along with my big cock.
你想去勾引龙女王？
You're going to seduce the Dragon Queen?
不用我勾引 这支舰队会让她上钩
I'm not going to seduce her. The Iron Fleet will seduce her.
然后我就和她一起夺占七国
And together we're going to take the Seven Kingdoms.
我不是天生的国王
I wasn't born to be king.
但我已经付了
I paid the iron price
登上王位的铁钱
and here I stand.
攸伦 ！攸伦 ！攸伦 ！攸伦 ！
Euron! Euron! Euron! Euron!
攸伦 ！攸伦 ！
Euron! Euron!
让您的仆人 攸伦 如您一般自海中重生
May Euron, your servant, be born again from the sea as you were.
给予他海盐的祝福 给与他坚石的祝福
Bless him with salt. Bless him with stone.
给予他钢铁的祝福
Bless him with steel.
倾听海浪 倾听神灵
Listen to the waves. Listen to the god.
他晓谕我等
He is speaking to us and he says
只当拥立攸伦·葛雷乔伊为王
we shall have no king but Euron Greyjoy.
愿海洋洗去你的愚蠢和虚浮
Let the sea wash your follies and your vanities away.
让攸伦的旧驱壳受淹
Let the old Euron drown.
让海水充盈他的肺
Let his lungs fill with seawater.
让海鱼嗫去他的眼睑
Let the fish eat the scales off his eyes.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die,
必将再起 其势更烈
but rises again harder and stronger.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
我的侄子侄女在哪儿？
Where are my niece and nephew?
让我们去杀掉他们
Let's go murder them.
他们偷走了我们最好的船
They stole our best ships.
带走多少也救不了他们
Won't be enough to save them.
回到你们的领地去
Go back to your homes.
见树就砍
Chop down every tree you can find.
锯好木材就开工造船
Quarter-saw the timber and start building.
每一个男人都来给我打造甲板
I want every man bending planks.
每一个女人都来给我编织帆布
I want every woman spinning flax for sails.
为我打造一千条长船
Build me a thousand ships
我会给你们整个世界
and I will give you this world.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
弥林的女王
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
我放逐了你两次
I banished you twice.
你回来了两次
You came back twice.
达里奥·纳哈里斯
雇佣兵
然后你救了我的命
And you saved my life.
所以我既不能接纳你
So I can't take you back
也不能赶你走
and I can't send you away.
你必须赶我走
You must send me away.
有治愈的方法吗？
Is there a cure?
我不知道
I don't know.
还剩多少时间？
How long does it take?
我也不知道
I don't know that either.
但我见过它恶化后的样子
But I've seen what happens when it goes far enough.
在那之前 我会把事情了结
I'll end things before that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
不必如此
Don't be.
我唯一想要的就是为您效命
All I've ever wanted was to serve you.
提利昂·兰尼斯特是对的
Tyrion Lannister was right.
我爱你
I love you.
我会永远爱你
I'll always love you.
再见 卡丽熙
Good-bye, khaleesi.
不要背弃你的女王
Do not walk away from your queen,
安达尔人乔拉
Jorah the Andal.
我还没有遣散你
You have not been dismissed.
你发誓效忠于我
You pledged yourself to me.
你发誓一生遵从我的命令
You swore to obey my commands for the rest of your life.
那么我命令你找到解药
Well, I command you to find the cure
天涯海角也在所不辞
wherever it is in this world.
我命令你治愈自己
I command you to heal yourself
再回到我身边
and then return to me.
当我征服七大王国时
When I take the Seven Kingdoms,
我需要你在我身边
I need you by my side.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
和奴隶主们签订合约后的半个月里
In the last fortnight since our pact with the Masters,
鹰身女妖之子杀了多少人？
how many killings have been carried out by the Sons of the Harpy?
一个也没有
None.
自由人杀了多少奴隶主呢？
And how many Masters have been butchered by the free men?
两个 不过都是在签订合约当天
Two, but that was the day of the pact.
自那以后就没有了
Since then, nothing.
所以不过分地说 脆弱的和平已经达成
So it's safe to say that a fragile peace has taken hold.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
灰虫子
弥桑黛
暂时如此
For now.
“暂时”是我们目前能得到的最好结果
For now is the best we get in our profession.
这还不够
It's not enough.
考虑到城市之前已经处在内战边缘
Considering the city was on the brink of civil war,
这算是个不错的开始啊
I'd say it's a good start.
他们不仅仅需要知道弥林已经和平
It's not enough for Meereen to have peace.
更要知道是丹妮莉丝造就的和平
They need to know Daenerys is responsible for it.
鹰身女妖之子有个好故事
The Sons of the Harpy have a good story.
抵抗外来入侵者
Resist the foreign invaders.
我们的女王有个更好的故事
Our queen has an even better story.
龙之母、解放者……所有这些
Mother of Dragons, Breaker of Chains... all that.
人们知道是谁带给他们自由的
The people know who brought them freedom.
没错 但他们知道是谁带给他们安全吗
Yes, but do they know who brought them security?
是谁终结了暴力？
Who brought about an end to the violence?
我们需要一个人们信任的人
We need someone the people trust,
一个他们知道不可能被收买或被影响的人
someone they know cannot be bought or influenced.
听上去是个大英雄啊 我们上哪儿去找他？
Sounds like quite the hero. Where would we find him?
谁说是“他”了
Who said anything about "him"?
你面前的是
You stand in the presence of Kinvara,
瓦兰提斯红神庙的至高牧师辛瓦拉
High Priestess of the Red Temple of Volantis,
真相之火
the Flame of Truth,
睿智之光
the Light of Wisdom,
光之王的首仆
the First Servant of the Lord of Light.
欢迎来到弥林
Welcome to Meereen.
这大概是我瓦雷利亚语的极限了
That's about the extent of my Valyrian.
感谢您远道至此
Thank you for travelling all this way.
我亲身体会过这趟旅途有多么令人不适
I know from personal experience how uncomfortable the journey can be.
事实是 我们需要您的帮助
The truth is we need your help.
我们希望可以劝说您……
We had hoped that we could somehow persuade you to...
你无需劝说我
You don't need to persuade me.
我就是来帮忙的
I came to help.
风暴降生丹妮莉丝是预言中的王子
Daenerys Stormborn is the one who was promised.
她从火焰中重生 将重塑这个世界
From the fire she was reborn to remake the world.
是的
Yes.
她打破了奴隶们的铁链
She has freed the slaves from their chains
将罪恶的奴隶主们钉上十字架
and crucified the Masters for their sins.
是的
She did indeed.
她的龙是火焰化身的血肉
Her dragons are fire made flesh,
是光之王的礼物
a gift from the Lord of Light.
但这些你都听过 不是吗？
But you heard all of this before, haven't you?
在瓦兰提斯的长桥上
On the Long Bridge of Volantis.
巨龙会净化成千上万的异端
The dragons will purify nonbelievers by the thousands,
把他们的罪恶和肉体焚烧殆尽
burning their sins and flesh away.
理想情况下 我们不想净化过多的异端
Ideally we'd avoid purifying too many nonbelievers.
龙之母有很多不同信仰的追随者
The Mother of Dragons has followers of many different faiths.
你想要你的女王被崇拜和服从
You want your queen to be worshipped and obeyed.
在她缺席期间 你还想要她的顾问们
And while she's gone, you want her advisors
被崇拜和服从
to be worshipped and obeyed.
服从就够了
I'd settle for obeyed.
我会召来我最有说服力的祭司们
I will summon my most eloquent priests.
他们会把我的话散播出去
They will spread the word.
丹妮莉丝被派来带领人民对抗黑暗
Daenerys has been sent to lead the people against the darkness
不仅是这场战争 还有未来的大战
in this war and in the great war still to come.
听起来很棒
That sounds most excellent.
你们的一个红袍女祭司曾宣称
A man named Stannis Baratheon was anointed
被选中的是一个叫史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的人
as the chosen one by one of your priestesses.
他同样怀有伟大使命
He, too, had a glorious destiny.
结果他进军君临 被打得落花流水
He attacked King's Landing and was soundly defeated
打败他的人就是我身边这位
by the man standing beside me.
上次我听说 他又被打败了
Last I had heard, he had been defeated again,
这次是在临冬城 他彻底歇菜了
this time at Winterfell and this time for good.
我们对您能提供给女王的任何支持都表示感谢
We'd be most grateful for any support you could provide the queen.
我想身为狂热者的人 应该很难承认错误
I suppose it's hard for a fanatic to admit a mistake.
这不正是狂信徒的意义所在吗？
Isn't that the whole point of being a fanatic?
你们永远是对的
You're always right.
一切都是真主的旨意
Everything is the Lord's will.
但是凡人都可能会犯错误
But men and women make mistakes.
即便是光之王的忠仆也在所难免
Even honest servants of the Lord.
所以您呢 光之王的忠仆
And you, an honest servant of the Lord,
我们如何相信您知道的
why should I trust you to know any more
比谏言史坦尼斯的那位更多？
than the priestess who counseled Stannis?
我的朋友对信仰怀有一些合理的疑惑
My friend has a healthy skepticism of religion,
然而我们都是女王陛下忠诚的支持者
but we are all loyal supporters of the queen.
每个人变成什么样子
Everyone is what they are
身处何地 都是有原因的
and where they are for a reason.
可怕的事情发生也有原因
Terrible things happen for a reason.
比如幼年时期发生在你身上的事 瓦里斯大人
Take what happened to you, Lord Varys, when you were a child.
如果你没有在一个二流术士手上被阉割
If not for your mutilation at the hand of a second-rate sorcerer,
你怎会在这里帮助真主的选民将光明带给世界？
you wouldn't be here helping the Lord's Chosen bring his light into the world.
知识让你变得强大
Knowledge has made you powerful.
但是你不知道的事情还太多太多
But there's still so much you don't know.
你还记得那天晚上听到了什么
Do you remember what you heard that night
当术士将你那话儿扔进火中的时候？
when the sorcerer tossed your parts in the fire?
你听到了火焰中的声音 还记得吗？
You heard a voice call out from the flames. Do you remember?
要我告诉你那声音说了什么吗？
Should I tell you what the voice said?
要我告诉你发出声音的是谁吗？
Should I tell you the name of the one who spoke?
我们效忠同一个女王
We serve the same queen.
如果你是她真正的朋友
If you are her true friend,
就无需怕我
you have nothing to fear from me.
什么？
What?
他看见我了 夜王！
He saw me, the Night King!
- 他看见我了！ - 他碰了你
- He saw me! - He touched you.
我不知道 他离我很近 但是……
I don't know. He was close, but...
他碰了你
He touched you.
他知道你在这 他会来找你
He knows you are here. He'll come for you.
但他进不来
But he can't get in.
现在他可以了 他已经标记了你
He can now. His mark is on you.
你必须离开 你们全部
You must leave, all of you.
梅拉·黎德
过来 阿多 帮我准备雪橇
Come on, Hodor. Help me with the sledge.
阿多
Hodor.
对不起 我不是故意的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
- 是时候了 - 什么时候？
- The time has come. - The time for what?
你成为我的时候
For you to become me.
但我准备好了吗？
But am I ready?
没有
No.
我们不能一边从北面抵御异鬼
We can't defend the north from the walkers
曼德勒家族
葛洛佛家族
霍伍德家族
莫尔蒙家族
佛雷家族
徒利家族
河安家族
波顿家族
安柏家族
史塔克家族
（黑城堡）
卡史塔克家族
临冬城
（波顿）
(赛文)
北
→
一边从南面抵御波顿
and the south from the Boltons.
我们需要临冬城
If we want to survive, we need Winterfell
琼恩·雪诺
而想拿下临冬城 我们需要更多人手
and to take Winterfell, we need more men.
除了史塔克和波顿
Aside from the Starks and the Boltons,
北境最有势力的家族是
the most powerful houses in the North
安柏家族 卡史塔克家族
are the Umbers, the Karstarks,
还有曼德勒家族
and the Manderlys.
安柏家族和卡史塔克家族
The Umbers and the Karstarks
已宣布效忠波顿家族
have already declared for the Boltons,
所以我们这里的情况不太妙
so we're not doing so well there.
安柏家把瑞肯交给了我们的敌人 他们都该被绞死
The Umbers gave Rickon to our enemies. They can hang.
但卡史塔克家宣誓效忠拉姆斯时
But the Karstarks declared for Ramsay
并不知道他们还有其他选择
without knowing they had another choice.
对不起 夫人
I beg your pardon, my lady,
但他们知道史塔克家砍了他们族长的头
but they know that a Stark beheaded their father.
我不觉得还能指望他们
I don't think we can count on them either.
你对北境有多了解呢 戴佛斯爵士
How well do you know the North, Ser Davos?
几乎不了解 夫人
Precious little, my lady.
我父亲总说 北境人与众不同
My father always said Northerners are different.
更忠实 对外人更猜忌
More loyal, more suspicious of outsiders.
他们或许忠实
They may well be loyal,
但当波顿背叛你的家族时
but how many rose up against the Boltons
又有多少人敢站出来对抗他们呢？
when they betrayed your family?
我可能不了解北境 但我了解人性
I may not know the North, but I know men.
无论在世界的哪个角落 他们基本是一样的
They're more or less the same in any corner of the world
哪怕最勇敢的人也不想看着
and even the bravest of them don't want to see
自己的妻儿因战败被剥皮
their wives and children skinned for a lost cause.
琼恩要想说服他们并肩作战
If Jon's going to convince them to fight alongside him,
就要让他们知道我们有赢的把握
they need to believe it's a fight they can win.
北境不止有三个家族……
There are more than three other houses in the North...
葛洛佛 莫尔蒙 赛文
Glover, Mormont, Cerwyn,
梅辛 霍伍德
Mazin, Hornwood.
二十多个 加在一起足以和其他人抗衡
Two dozen more. Together they equal all the others.
忧郁的艾迪
守夜人
我们可以积少成多
We can start small and build.
北境永不遗忘
The North remembers.
托蒙德
野人头领
他们不会遗忘史塔克这个姓氏
They remember the Stark name.
从白港到拉姆斯的门前
People will still risk everything for it,
一定有人仍愿意为史塔克付出一切
from White Harbor to Ramsay's own door.
毫无疑问
I don't doubt it.
但琼恩并不姓史塔克
But Jon doesn't have the Stark name.
是 但我姓史塔克
No, but I do.
琼恩就是奈德·史塔克的儿子
Jon is every bit as much Ned Stark's son
好比拉姆斯是卢斯·波顿的儿子
as Ramsay is Roose Bolton's.
还有很多徒利家的人 他们虽然不是北境人
And there are also the Tullys. They're not Northern,
但仍会毫不犹豫的支持我们对抗波顿
but they will back us against the Boltons without question.
我不知道徒利家还有军队
I didn't know the Tullys still had an army.
我外叔祖父黑鱼重组军队 夺回了奔流城
My uncle the Blackfish has reformed it and retaken Riverrun.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
在我逃离临冬城前 拉姆斯收到渡鸦带来的消息
Ramsay received a raven before I escaped Winterfell.
这很好
That's good.
黑鱼是个传奇
The Blackfish is a legend.
他的支持对我们而言意义重大
His support would mean a great deal.
史塔克 徒利 加上其他家族
Stark, Tully, a few more houses,
总算看起来有些胜算了
almost starts to look like a winning side.
我发过誓要保护你 夫人
I've sworn to protect you, my lady.
你听到了 我们需要更多人手
You heard them. We need more men
而我外叔祖父有只军队
and my uncle has an army.
我们可以给黑鱼送只渡鸦
We can send the Blackfish a raven.
被拉姆斯截获的话就完了
Can't risk Ramsay intercepting it.
必须由你传达
It has to be you.
骑马去奔流城 我外叔祖父会和你谈的
Ride for Riverrun. My uncle will talk to you
你也知道怎么跟他说
and you'll know how to talk to him.
怎么了？
What is it?
我不想把你单独留在这
I don't like leaving you here alone.
因为琼恩？
With Jon?
不是他 他看上去很可靠
Not him. He seems trustworthy.
可能有点阴郁
A bit brooding, perhaps.
不过考虑到他的经历 也可以理解
I suppose that's understandable, considering.
但其他人
The others, though.
戴佛斯和红袍女是某人谋杀亲弟弟的共谋
Davos and the Red Woman helped a man murder his own brother
使用血魔法
with bloodmagic.
而当史坦尼斯为自己的罪行付出代价时 他们在哪儿？
And when Stannis paid for his crime, where were they?
已经离开他 去寻找更有前途的领头人了
Already out looking for a leader with better prospects.
还有那个留着络腮胡的野人……
And that wildling fellow with the beard...
琼恩不是托蒙德 他不是戴佛斯 也不是红袍女
Jon isn't Tormund. Jon isn't Davos, the Red Woman
他也不是史坦尼斯 琼恩就是琼恩
or Stannis for that matter. Jon is Jon.
他是我哥哥 他会保护我的 我相信他
He's my brother. He'll keep me safe. I trust him.
那他问你怎么知道奔流城的事的时候 你为什么要骗他？
Then why did you lie to him when he asked you how you learned about Riverrun?
新衣服？
New dress?
我自己做的 你喜欢吗？
I made it myself. Do you like it?
是的 它很…… 我喜欢这个狼的刺绣
Yeah, it's... I like the wolf bit.
那就好 因为我给你做了这个
Good, because I made this for you.
我仿着父亲常穿的那件做的
I made it like the one Father used to wear.
仿着我记忆中的样子
As near as I can remember.
谢谢你 珊莎
Thank you, Sansa.
不客气
You're welcome.
我走之后 别把这搞垮了
Don't knock it down while I'm gone.
我会尽力的
I'll do my best.
祝你好运
Good luck.
关上大门吗 总司令？
Should we close the gate, Lord Commander?
我不是总司……
I'm not the Lord Comman...
好吧…… 关上这该死的门
yeah... close the bloody gate.
我们可以回家啦 阿多
We can go home now, Hodor.
好吧 可能不是那个家
Well, maybe not home home,
但至少不用再待在山洞里了
but somewhere that isn't a cave.
阿多
Hodor.
吃点苔藓以外的食物
Eat something that isn't moss.
我想吃鸡蛋 你喜欢鸡蛋吗？
I want an egg. How do you like 'em?
煮鸡蛋？ 或者用黄油煎一下？
Boiled? Fried up with some butter?
阿多
Hodor.
配上片熏肉 加上些血肠
With a rasher of bacon and some blood sausage.
阿多
Hodor.
带上布兰 快跑！
Get Bran and run!
布兰 布兰 醒醒！
Bran. Bran, wake up.
-布兰！ -阿多 阿多
- Bran. - Hodor. Hodor.
布兰 醒醒
Bran, wake up.
诸神会保佑你在国王大道上一路平安 保重
Gods keep you on the kingsroad. Take it easy.
小心点
Watch yourself.
阿多
Hodor.
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
帮帮我！
Help me!
撤！
Go!
记住你是史塔克家的人
Remember that you are a Stark.
在谷地要举止庄重
Comport yourself with dignity at the Vale
尽量别打架
and try to stay out of fights.
好的 父亲
Yes, Father.
艾德·史塔克
如果不得不打的话
But if you have to fight,
瑞卡德·史塔克
一定要赢
win.
布兰 布兰 醒醒！
Bran! Bran, wake up!
布兰！布兰！布兰 醒醒！
Bran! Bran! Bran, wake up.
-布兰！布兰 醒醒！ -阿多 阿多
- Bran! Bran, wake up! - Hodor. Hodor.
你快醒过来
You have to wake up.
-我们需要阿多 -阿多 阿多
- We need Hodor. - Hodor. Hodor.
布兰 我们需要阿多
Bran, we need Hodor.
布兰 快醒过来你 我们需要阿多
Bran, you have to wake up. We need Hodor.
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
布兰 我们快死了！
Bran, we're all going to die!
布兰 快醒醒！
Bran, wake up!
我们都要死了！布兰！布兰！
We're all going to die! Bran! Bran!
布兰 快醒醒 我们需要阿多
Bran, you have to wake up. We need Hodor.
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
快控制阿多！
Warg into Hodor now!
布兰 醒醒 我们需要阿多
Bran, wake up. We need Hodor.
我们需要阿多 快控制他！快！
We need Hodor. Warg into Hodor now! Now!
听听你朋友的呼唤 布兰登
Listen to your friend, Brandon.
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
-夏天！ -撤！
- Summer! - Go.
快撤！
Go!
时间到了
The time has come.
走吧
Leave me.
-你在干嘛？ -快走！
- What are you doing? - Go!
阿多 快！
Hodor, hurry!
阿多！
Hodor!
Hold the door! (把门堵住！)
把门堵住！威利斯！
Hold the door! Wylis!
出什么事了？
What's the matter?
-把门堵住！ -坚持住 儿子
- Hold the door! - Come on, son.
Hold the door! (把门堵住！)
Hold the door! Hold the door! (把门堵住！把门堵住！)
Hold the door! Hold the door!(把门堵住！把门堵住！)
Hold the door! Hold door!（把门堵住！啊堵住！）
Hold door! Hold the door!（啊堵住！把门堵住！）
Hold the door! Hold door! Hold door （把门堵住！啊堵住！啊堵住！）
Hold door! Hodor!（啊堵住！阿多！）
Hodor! Hodor!（阿多！阿多！）
Hodor!（阿多！）
衣柜字幕组出品
本集关键字：选王会
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？
维基新站网址：HTTP://AsoIaF.HuiJi.WiKi